Luong Van Tu

luongvantuit@gmail.com

+84965445305

GitHub

SUMMARY

I'm Software Engineer. I have 1 year experience in Backend & Ops. I'm a person who is passionate about learning new things, especially in the field of technology. I'm a person who is always willing to learn and share knowledge with others.

SKILLS

- Languages: Javascript, Typescript,....
- Frameworks: React, React Native, NextJS, NodeJS, TailwindCSS, Express, NestJS.
- Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL.
- DevOps: CI/CD (Bitbucket Pipeline, Github Action, Jenkins), Docker, Kubernetes, Git, Terraform, NGINX.

EDUCATION

University of Science, Vietnam National University Hanoi - Ha Noi, Vietnam

October 2019 - Present

Computer and Information Science

Experience

AusVie

Logistics - Mobile Developer

December 2023 - March 2023

- **Description:** Build a mobile application for staff update information of order (Confirm Booking, Unit Packing,...).
- Technologies: React Native, Redux, Camera Vision.
- Responsibilities:
 - Create UI from Figma design.
 - Make all screens: Scan QR Pallet, Update Step (Confirm Booking, Unit Packing),...
 - Interact with REST API (form-data, application/json).
 - Manager state application with Redux (Authentication,...).
 - Deploy application to Testflight, App Store Connect.

Logistics - Backend Developer

August 2022 - December 2022

• **Description:** Build a headless CMS from Strapi (Open source) for logistics company between Australia & Vietnam.

- Technologies: Strapi CMS, Bitbucket Pipeline, Docker.
- Responsibilities:
 - o Develop backend custom Strapi REST API for transit pallet, order...
 - Calculate price of booking and response to user when have request a REST API to server, config CI/CD.
 - Manager roles of system: User, Admin, Staff.
 - Make routes for requests update information of order by staff & send information a quote for user when have booking to email.

Logistics - DevOps

June 2022 - August 2022

- Responsibilities:
 - Config Terraform for deploy to AWS Web Services.
- **Technologies:** Terraform, AWS(EC2, S3 Bucket, VPC, LB,...).
- Architecture: Terraform (AWS Web Services)
 - Source Demo Basic Terraform demo with AWS Web Services. Use terraform to create VPC, EC2, RDS, S3.
 - In future: I will use this demo to apply services advanced (Auto Scaling, ECS .v.v.).

AusVie (On Job Training) - Backend Developer

February 2022 - June 2022

- **Description:** Learning NestJS and apply to build a backend for a project GraphQl API for ECommerce-site.
- Technologies: NestJS, Docker.
- Database: MongoDB.
- Responsibilities:
 - Develop backend config base project.
 - Learn apply Agile Scrum on Jira.
 - Define authorization JWT for authentication system.

Rogo Solutions

Rogo Hotel - Frontend Developer (Collaborator)

April 2022 - Jun 2022

- Description:
 - Rogo Hotel App Desktop is a hotel manager booking application for reception. Reception can
 use book hotel, check-in, check-out for customer. With this application, reception can manage
 hotel more easily.
 - Mobile App when customer check-in hotel, they can use this app to control device in room, order food.
- Technologies:
 - Frameworks: ReactJS, Electron, MQTT, NodeJS, Express.
 - Tools: Webpack, MQTT Paho Client.
 - **Device**: Desktop (Windows, Linux, MacOS), Mobile (IPad, IPhone).
- Responsibilities:
 - Develop desktop application with ElectronJS, ReactJS (Render).
 - Develop mobile application with SwiftUI.
 - Manage book room for hotel.

CHIP (Connected Home IP) - Research (Collaborator)

December 2021 - Jun 2022

• **Description:**: Research protocol Master with CHIP project, build Android application ability add new device to network.

Rogo Partner - Frontend Developer (Intern)

March 2020 - Sep 2020

- **Description:** This is a website for manage sell device of partner Rogo Solutions. Admin can manage partner add new or delete partner.
- Technologies:
 - Frameworks: Flutter (Dart).
 - o Tools: Docker.
- Responsibilities:
 - Develop website with Flutter web.
 - UI/UX manager partner of Rogo Solutions.

ACTIVITIES

Build On Vietnam 2021

August 2021 - Sep 2021

- **Description:** Join with Techcombank FACT team to recommend & demo a solution for Techcombank. This application help customer can manage their account, money more easily.
- Finalist Build On Contest Certificates

HAMIC - HUS Applied Mathematics and Informatics Club

June 2021 - Present

- Head of Design & Development Web
- The organizers of the club's activities, such as: WContest: Web for Education.